AMAN MATHUR

+91 8890629848 ♦ Gurgaon, Haryana, India

aman1997mathur@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIN ♦ Github ♦ HackerRank

SUMMARY

A Software developer with **5 years** of experience in software designing and development. A personable, communicative developer who contributes to all phases of development cycle, act as an individual contributor and collaborator and ability to write well designed, testable and efficient code.

SKILLS

Technical Skills Java, Spring Boot, SQL, PLSQL, AWS, UNIX, LINUX, Shell Script

Certifications AWS – Certified AWS Cloud Practitioner

EXPERIENCE

Software DeveloperJan, 2022 - PresentAmdocsGurgaon, Haryana

- Working for a telecom application ECOM (OSS/BSS) for processing orders received from CRM.
- Development of REST APIs to connect with external system for order processing using front-end as Angular, and Spring Boot.
- For bulk data management Spring-batch jobs were written and deployed in Control-M tool.
- Got opportunity to work with client at location **Singapore**.

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services Ltd

Jul, 2019 - Dec, 2021

Gurgaon, Haryana

- Worked on TCS BANCS a banking/financial domain product on Spring Boot, Spring MVC and JAVA.
- Implemented banking functionalities by creating web-services and SHELL SCRIPTS for batch processing.

Intern

May, 2019 – Jul, 2019

Smartron India Pvt Ltd Hyderabad, Telangana

- Worked on Maya, a speech recognition and IOT project.
- Wrote a C subroutine to control a light bulb connected with a smart switch using Z-wave protocol, Z-wave Application, Open WRT Basics.

PROJECTS

Face Recognition System - Developed a system which can recognize human face using Python and OpenCV (Source Code)

Digit Recognition System - Developed a system which is capable of understanding digits made using tools like paint, using Python and OpenCV (Source Code)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology, Jaypee Institute of Information Technology (JIIT, NOIDA)

2015 - 2019

• Cumulative CGPA: 6.6; Major in Electronics & Communication